Guide to the Gitel P. Steed Papers 1907-1980
University of Chicago Library
- Series IV: Nawabpur Files, 1951
  - Subseries 6: Topical Files
    - Zamindar Abolition Act in Uttar Pradesh, interview, 1952 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Jajmani relations, tehelva-thikana (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Art notes by John Koos (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Questionnaires, district map, clippings, ratings, 1950, undated (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, booklets, McKim Marriott notes, correspondence from villagers, genealogy, photographs, 1951, undated (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 7: General Notebooks, Gitel P. Steed
    - I, II, Aligarh, TAT, accounts, January 18-February 21 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - II, index (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - III, IV, unnumbered informant, February 24-March 28 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - V, VI, Rorschach, March 1-April 6 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - VII, VIII, unnumbered informant, Rorschach, March 3-July 19 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - IX, X, Informant 4, March 8-24 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - XI, medical survey, women, March 9-July 7 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - XII, XIII, TAT 1-5, March 9-28 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - XIV, XV, Informant 1, March 14-April 7 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - XVI, XVII, unnumbered informant, March 18-April 14 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - XVIII, XIX, March 24-April 1 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - XX, XXI, unnumbered informant, H-H, accounts for 1949-1951, March 29-May 1 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - XXII, XXIII, unnumbered informant, March 30-August 5 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - XXIV, XXV, Rorschach, women, April 7-13 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - XV, XVI, urban tests, TAT 6-14, March 30-July 12 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - XVII, XVIII, Informant 1, April 11-13 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - XXIX, unnumbered informant, April 13 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 8: General Notebooks by others
    - XXX, XXXI, kinship, women, July 16-August 8 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - XXXII, XXXIII, tests, records, August 15-September 5 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - XXXIV, XXXV, personal narrations, Rorschach, July 16-September 29 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - XXXVI-XXXVII, religion, July 23-October 1 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - XXXVIII-XXXIX, jajmani relations, kinship, August 6-September 4 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - XL, sketches by John Koos, land, July 8-September 13 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - XLI, XLII, women, August 11-29 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - XLII, XLIII, personal narration, jajmani relations, August 15-October 4 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - XLIV, XLV, jajmani relations, women (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - XLVI, XLVII, Rorschach, TAT, women, September 29-October 4 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - XLVIII, XLIX, women, ratings, October 1-6 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - L, LI, women, September 25-October 10 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - LII, LIII, caste and personality traits, October 6-10 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - LIV, religion, caste and personality traits, October 7-10 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Unnumbered, jajmani relations, September 17-28 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Unnumbered, Rorschachs, September 27-October 3 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Unnumbered, Rorschachs, September 27-October 3 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Unnumbered, TAT, September 17-November 12 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Unnumbered, TAT, September 17-November 12 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Unnumbered, shorthand notes, undated (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Unnumbered, loose notes, March-April (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Unnumbered, loose notes, TAT, April 4 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Land survey, July 8-September 9 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Child health survey, May 4 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Accounts, receipts, February-October (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Accounts, receipts, February-October (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 9: General Notebooks, James Silverberg
    - I, II, February 22-March 6 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - III, IV, kinship, March 7-11 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - V, VI, unnumbered informant, kinship, March 9-15 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - VII, VIII, unnumbered informant, Rorschach, March 13-April 21 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - IX, X, TAT, kinship, March 16-May 3 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - XI, XII, unnumbered informant, kinship, March 20-May 5 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - XIII, XIV, Color Association, kinship, March 26-May 5 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - XVI, XVII, unnumbered informant, Draw-a-man kinship, April 5-May 27 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - XVI, XVII, unnumbered informant, Draw-a-man kinship, April 5-May 27 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - XVIII, XIX, unnumbered informant, kinship chart, April 9-May 28 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - XVIII, XIX, unnumbered informant, kinship chart, April 9-May 28 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - XX, XXI, unnumbered informant, April 14, May 23 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - XXII, XXIII, Informant 1, Rorschachs, April 21-May 21 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - XXIV, XXV, Land Utilization Survey, April 22-May 8 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - XXV, XXVI, unnumbered informant, H-H, April 20-May 27 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - XXVII, XXVIII, TAT, H-H, April 25-May 7 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - XXIX, XXX, Rorschach, Color Association, April 24-May 27 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - XXIX, XXX, Rorschach, Color Association, April 24-May 27 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - XXXI, XXXII, Rorschach, April 29-May 6 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - XXXIII, XXXIV, Informant 4, H-H, drawings, May 3-27 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - XXXV, XXXVI, Rorschach, Color Association, May 6-27 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - XXXV, XXXVI, Rorschach, Color Association, May 6-27 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - XXXVII, XXIX, TAT, May 7-16 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - XL, XLI, Rorschach, May 10-19 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - XLII, XLIII, TAT, kinship, May 15-22 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - XLIV, XLV, Rorschach, May 19-25 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - XLVI, XLVII, XLVIII, Rorschach, TAT, H-H, May 7-27 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 10: Notebooks by others
    - Tahera, I, II, February 25-April 5 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Tahera, III, IV, April 8-May 9 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Tahera, V, May 9-26 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Tahera, V, May 3 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Unnumbered informant, I, II, Rorschach, Color Association, February 10- May 9 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Unnumbered informant, III, TAT, April 19-May 18 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Unnumbered informant, Draw-a-man, February 27-May 22 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Unnumbered informant, Color Association, general, April 9-May 4 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 11: Drawings
    - Informant list (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Tabulations (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Watercolors, Informants 1-22 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Watercolors, Informants 23-38 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Watercolors, Informants 39-57 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Watercolors, Informants 58-86 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Watercolors, visitors' (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Watercolors, unidentified (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Drawings, Informant list (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Drawings, Draw-a-man (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - House and wall drawings, John Koos (Box 72, Folder 7)
- Series V: Deoli Files, 1950
  This series contains five subseries and includes the typewritten notes and data collected by G. Morris Carstairs while in Deoli, the third village included in the India project. Carstairs worked for the most part alone and stayed in the village for approximately six months. A psychiatrist, Carstairs was mostly interested in life history material, and therefore the bulk of his data is on particular individuals.
  - Subseries 1: Informant Life Histories
    - Informant list (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Informant list (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Informant 1 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Informant 3 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Informant 4 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Informant 5 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Informant, unnumbered (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 2: Psychodiagnostic Tests
    - Rorschach 1-52, March 16-May 20 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Rorschach 1-52, March 16-May 20 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Rorschach, H-H, unidentified informant (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - TAT, 1-48, March 15-31 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - TAT, re-presentations, May 18 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - TAT, "Observations on use of TAT in Deoli Village," Panna Lal Shrimali and G. Morris Carstairs, manuscript, May 18 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Horn-Hellersberg (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Color Association Test (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Child Development Test, 1949-1950 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 3: General Notes, G. Morris Carstairs
    - January 14-January 31, February 21 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - February 1-28 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - March 1-29 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - April 20-30 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - May 1-22 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - May 23-27 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - May 28-June 6 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - June 7-16 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Wedding data, February 27-March 12 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Regars, May 24-June 12 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Children, May 23-June 15 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Marriage relations, house plan, religion, disputes, manuscript, 1950-1951 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clipping (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Notes, photograph (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 4: Field Notebooks, G. Morris Carstairs
    - Diary I, December 28, 1949-January 24, 1950 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Diary I, inserted notes (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Diary II, January 24-May 22, 1950 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Hindi vocabulary (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Hindi and Roman Urdu texts, Gitel P. Steed dictation (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Field notebook X, March 30-April 20, 1950 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Horn-Hellersberg tests, January 2-April 16, 1950 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Material Culture, unidentified author (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 5: Drawings
    - Informant list (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Tabulations by sex, age, and caste (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Colored pencil drawings (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Colored pencil drawings (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Colored pencil drawings, visitors' (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Colored pencil drawings, unidentified (Box 75, Folder 8)
- Series VI: Art Work by Gitel and Robert Steed
  This series contains 70 photographs by Gitel Steed as well as the artwork of Robert Steed, an artist by profession. Most of Steed's photographs are believed to come from Kasandra, though some from Nawabpur are included as well. These black-and-white photographs portray parents and children, gods and rituals, and a variety of village scenes. Some of her India photographs appeared in Edward Steichen's exhibit on "The Family of Man" at the Museum of Modern Art in New York in 1955 and are reproduced in the book of the same title. Several negatives are also included in the series.
  Robert Steed, having accompanied his wife to India, spent a great deal of his time sketching the villagers, their houses, shrines, etc. The collection here includes small pencil sketches on index cards, color and black-and-white xeroxes of other sketches still in the possession of the Steed family, and several watercolors of villagers and of village religious sites.
  - Subseries 1: Photographs by Gitel P. Steed, 1950-1951
    - See Oversize Series for contents (Box 85)
  - Subseries 2: Robert Steed Drawings and Paintings, 1950-1951
    - Portraits, pencil on index cards, 39 cards (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Portraits, drawings (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Portraits, watercolors (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Portraits, color and black and white photocopies, notes by James Silverberg and McKim Marriott, 95 sketches (Box 75, Folder 12)
- Series VII: Audio-Visual Materials
  - Subseries 1: Film
    - India, 1950 (Reel 1)
    - India, 1950 (Reel 2)
  - Subseries 2: Sound Recordings
    - Field interviews, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Tape 1)
    - Field interviews, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Tape 2)
    - Field interviews, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Tape 3)
    - Field interviews, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Tape 4)
    - Field interviews, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Tape 5)
    - Field interviews, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Tape 6)
    - Field interviews, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Tape 7)
    - Field interviews, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Tape 8)
    - Field interviews, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Tape 9)
    - Field interviews, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Tape 10)
    - Field interviews, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Tape 11)
    - Gitel P. Steed, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 75, Reel 12)
    - Gitel P. Steed, dictation, February, 1959, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 76, Reel 13)
    - Gitel P. Steed, discussing "Devgar," undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 76, Reel 14)
    - Unidentified, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 76, Reel 15)
    - Wire recording, spool 1: Bakrana, first recording, children's songs (Ahmedabad), village singers, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 77)
    - Wire recording, spool 2: Bakrana, marriage songs, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 77)
    - Wire recording, spool 3: Bakrana, mandali, October 30, 1950, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 77)
    - Wire recording, spool 4: Bakrana, the horrors of [illegible], bhajans, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 77)
    - Wire recording, spool 5: Bakrana, women's bhajan, abusive songs, undated, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 77)
    - Wire recording, spool 6: Nawabpur, March 29, 1951, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 77)
    - Wire recording, spool 7: Blank (Box 77)
    - Wire recording, spool 8: Unidentified, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 77)
    - Wire recording, spool 9: Unidentified, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 77)
    - Wire recording, spool 10: Unidentified, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 77)
    - Wire recording, spool 11: Unidentified, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 77)
- Series VIII: Manuscripts and Publications by Others
  This series contains manuscripts and publications that were in Steed's possession. These articles are on a wide variety of topics, primarily on India, and date from 1932 to 1977. Some of the manuscripts are early versions of what later became influential publications on India (the works of McKim Marriott and Bernard Cohn, for example). Most of the manuscripts in this series are on India.
  - Adji, Oemar Seno, "Asian Perspectives on the American Constitutional Influence," 1976 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - "Alternative Models for the American Family Structure," undated (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - American University, Bureau of Social Science Research, "Communication of Ideas in India: A Survey of Lucknow and Three Indian Villages," undated (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Andromedas, John N., "Clan Rank and Salvage Ethnography in Mani, Southern Greece," 1965 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - "Anthropology: A Review for the Teacher," undated (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Asia Society, Textbook Evaluation Project, book reviews, undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Bailey, F. G., "The Study of Politics in Village India," undated (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Barnett, Stephen A., "The Process of Withdrawal in a South ndian Caste, 1970 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Bennett, John W., "The Japanese Industrial Economy: Background for Social Change," 1963 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Bharati, Agehananda, "Hindu-American Culture Contact and the Hindu Renaissance," 1977 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Bhardwaj, S. M., "Socially Differentiated Religious Circulation: A View from the Sacred Centers," 1972 (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Blackwell, F. W., "Ambivalence and the City in the Fiction of R. Prawer Jhabvala," "The Perception of the Guru," 1976-1977 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Bombay Gazette, Indian Gazette, "Acts of Local Legislatures," 1950 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Bright, William, "A Study of Caste and Dialect in Mysore," undated (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Bruner, Jerome S., "Man: A Course of Study," undated (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - Bunzel, Ruth L., "Zuni Ritual Poetry," "Introduction to Zuni Ceremonialism," 1932 (Box 78, Folder 16)
  - Campbell, Joan M., "Persistance of the Cattle Complex in East Africa," 1967 (Box 78, Folder 17)
  - Champe, John L., "White Cat Village," photograph, 1949 (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - Chowdhury, Munier, "The Language Problem in East Pakistan." (Box 78, Folder 19)
  - Clark, Alice, "Female Infanticide as a Means of Maintaining Caste Dominance," 1976 (Box 78, Folder 20)
  - Cohn, Bernard S., "Some Notes on Law and Change in North India," 1959 (Box 78, Folder 21)
  - Cohn, Bernard S. and McKim Marriott, "Networks and Centres in the Integration of Indian Civilization," 1958 (Box 78, Folder 22)
  - "The Community and the Nation in Mexico," 1955 (Box 78, Folder 23)
  - Cornell, John B., "Dozoku: An Example of Evolution and Transition in Japanese Village Society," undated (Box 78, Folder 24)
  - Crane, R. I., "The City as a Catalyst for Group Political Development in India," undated (Box 78, Folder 25)
  - "Cultural Factors in Rural Community Development," undated (Box 78, Folder 26)
  - Damle, Y. B., "Communication of Modern Ideas and Knowledge in Indian Villages," 1955 (Box 78, Folder 27)
  - Danielou, Alain, "Religious Music of India," 1952 (Box 78, Folder 28)
  - Davies, C. Collin, "An Historical Atlas of the Indian Peninsula," fragment, 1949 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Dawar, L. R., "Market Practices in the Punjab," The Board of Economic Inquiry, Punjab, 1934 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - de Laguna, Grace A., "Cultural Relativism and Science," 1942 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Dimock, Edward C., outline and report on Indian languages, undated (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Engelman, Ralph M., "Germany's `Pentagon Papers'," undated (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Fales, Raymond L., "A Qualitative Index for the Distribution of City Sizes: United States and India," 1972 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - "Fear Itself: An Anthropologist's View," undated (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Fernando, Enrique M., "An Asian Perspective on the American Constitutional Influence in Asia: Its Impact on the Philippine Legal System," 1976 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Flemming, Leslie A., "Views of Urban Life in Recent Pakistani Fiction," undated (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Forward to Gaon: Conflict and Cohesion in an Indian Village by Henry Orenstein, 1965 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Frankel, Francine, "Land Tenure and Limits of Agrarian Modernization in India," 1975 (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - Frisch, Jack A., "A Formal Analysis of Sinhalese Kinship Terms," 1966 (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - Fusfield, Warren, "Religious Revitalization of the Ahmadiyya Movement," 1976 (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - Gemmill, Janet Powers, "Bombay, Madras, and Calcutta in the Indo-English Novel," undated (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Gough, Kathleen, "Criteria of Caste Ranking in South India," fragment, undated (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - Gross, Fredric J., "Trade and Commerce: Dentalia Shells on the Northwest Coast," 1964 (Box 79, Folder 16)
  - Guha, B. S., "Progress of Anthropological Research in India," 1949 (Box 79, Folder 17)
  - Guha, Kamalesh, "An Analysis of Primitive Food Production Technology in India.. .," undated (Box 79, Folder 18)
  - Gussow, Zachary and George S. Tracy, "Stigma and the Leprosy Phenomenon," 1968 (Box 79, Folder 19)
  - Hanchett, Suzanne, "Hindu Potlatches," 1973 (Box 79, Folder 20)
  - Hart, Henry C., "Bombay Politics: Pluralism or Polarization?" undated (Box 79, Folder 21)
  - Henry, Jules, "Cultural Discontinuity and the Shadow of the Past," 1948 (Box 79, Folder 22)
  - Hindi-Cheeni and D. Amba Bai, "Indian View of China before the Communist Revolution," 1955 (Box 79, Folder 23)
  - "Ichchangudi: An Agricultural Village in India," reprint, notes, undated (Box 79, Folder 24)
  - India, Government of, Information Services, newsletters, 1949 (Box 79, Folder 25)
  - India, Government of, National Library, Bibliography of Indian Anthropology, author index, 1951. (Box 79, Folder 26)
  - India, Government of, "A Tentative Bibliography of Basic Publications on all Aspects of Indian Culture, Section 1-Indian Anthropology," 1951. (Box 79, Folder 27)
  - Indian Council for Mental Hygiene, list of committees, "The Necessity of Preventative Mental Health," World Health Organization press release, undated (Box 79, Folder 28)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, "Rural Development Schemes in India," India paper No. 1, 1954. (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - "Introduction to Himalayan Area Study," 1963. (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Islam, A. K. M. Aminal, "National Ideologies and Village Change in Pakistan," undated (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Jenkins, Frances Briggs, Science Reference Sources, 1965. (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - "John MacDonald's paper for Peter Munro Jack - 1931" (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Joshi, Barbara Ravenell, "The Buddhist Movement in Uttar Pradesh and Autonomous Low Caste Mobilization," 1977 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Juergensmeyer, Mark, "When the Last Missionairies Left the Punjab," undated (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Khan, Mohammad I., "A Study of the Public Reaction against the British Administration in Avadh," 1976 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Khare, R.S., "Rethinking Caste Muddles," and "Predictions of Death among the Kanya-Kubja Brahmans," 1967 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Klass, Morton, "Approximating the `Peasant' in India," undated (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Kochar, V. K., book review of The Andaman Islanders by A. R. Radcliffe Brown, undated (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Leslie, Charles, "The Professionalization of Indigenous Medicine," correspondence, memorandum, 1969-1970 (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Lewis, Oscar, manuscripts, notes, 1953 (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - Lin, Sein, "An Integrated Approach to Economic Development Through Land Reform in Taiwan," undated (Box 80, Folder 14)
  - Maloney, Clarence, manuscripts, 1969-1972 (Box 80, Folder 15)
  - Mandelbaum, David G., "Form, Variation, and Meaning of a Ceremony," 1954 (Box 80, Folder 16)
  - Marriott, McKim, "Hindu Transactions: Diversity without Dualism," manuscript, report on textbooks, memorandum, 1973-1975 (Box 80, Folder 17)
  - Marriott, McKim, and Ronald B. Inden, "Towards an Ethnosociology of South Asian Caste Systems," 1973 (Box 80, Folder 18)
  - Marriott, McKim, "Caste Systems," 1973 (Box 80, Folder 19)
  - Martin, Kingsley, "The Next Five Year Plan in India," newspaper clippings, 1955 (Box 80, Folder 20)
  - Mayer, Albert, "Rural Research and Action Centre, Uttar Pradesh," memoranda, 1953 (Box 80, Folder 21)
  - Mazumdar, Debika De, "Child-rearing Practices among the Lodhas of West Bengal and Socialization," undated (Box 80, Folder 22)
  - McCormack, William, "Social Styles in Dharwar Kannada," undated (Box 80, Folder 23)
  - Mead, Margaret, Committee on Culture and Personality, National Research Council, questionnaire handbook, manuscripts, outline, correspondence, notes, 1953, undated (Box 80, Folder 24)
  - Meadows, Paul, "Industrial Man: Profiles of Developmental Society," 1965 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Miller, "Caste and Territory in Malabar, notes, undated (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Miner, Horace, "Body Ritual among the Nacirena," undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Oldenburg, Philip, "Briefing Materials on the Indian Parliamentary Elections, 1977," 1977 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Orenstein, Henry and Michael Micklin, reprints, manuscript, 1968-1970, undated (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Passin, Herbert, "Some Observations on Untouchability," undated (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Pillai, N. P. N., "Incidence of Suicide among Indian Women," abstract, notes, 1956 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Punjab, The Board of Economic Inquiry, village surveys 4, 6, 11, 1932-1938 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Punjab, The Board of Economic Inquiry, village surveys 4, 6, 11, 1932-1938 (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - Punjab, The Board of Economic Inquiry, village surveys 4, 6, 11, 1932-1938 (Box 81, Folder 10)